KATHRYN DIPIPPO

Newton, MA PHONE: (609) 751-7774 EMAIL: dipippo.k@gmail.com https://www.kathryndipippo.com/

Software developer specializing in full-stack development with a passion for intuitive design and optimization. Experienced in object-oriented programming and agile methodologies. Enthusiastic, dependable team player with strong project management and communication skills.

SKILLS

Languages: PHP, MySQL, Java, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, C++

Technologies/Frameworks: Git, Atlassian, Slack, Postman, Bootstrap, ¡Query, Materialize, Sketch, Photoshop,

Microsoft Office product suite, Google Drive product suite, Gmail

EXPERIENCE

Web and Mobile Applications Developer: Unbound Commerce - Newton, MA 40 hr/week; June 2017 - Present

- Develop Android applications for e-commerce clients utilizing both native checkout, most notably for Revel Nail,
 ProStockHockey, and Hudson Technologies
- Develop and maintain mobile e-commerce sites, most notably for Ashley Furniture and Restaurant Equippers
- Designed UX/UI using Sketch and Invision, most notably for ProStockHockey, WorkBoots USA, Luxmart.co
- Transformed static mocks into HTML/CSS/JS with intuitive animation flows

Consultant Intern: Tallan - Boston, MA

55 hr/week; May 2016 - August 2016

- Designed and implemented application customization feature in Virtual Tour internal program used by various clients, including the Massachusetts Legislature and Delaware Legislature
- Assisted in refactoring the "videos and special events" SQL database at the Massachusetts State House

Computer Science 1 Mentor: Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute - Troy, NY 6 hr/week; August 2015 - May 2017

Assisted Computer Science 1 students during lab & office hour periods for four semesters

REU Intern: MIRTHE Center - Princeton, MA

30 hr/week; Summer 2014 and 2015

- Participated on a research team to develop a device that measures a user's blood glucose levels using mid-infrared lasers
- 2014: implemented a MatLab GUI to be used by research students for further system testing
- 2015: refactored the GUI in Python to be used by patients at diabetic facilities for clinical trials
- Presented project at the concluding week-long MIRTHE conference

PROJECTS

Jabberwock-Isle: https://jabberwock-isle.com/

July 2018 - Present

- Designed and implemented an inventory tracker and trading center after seeing members struggle with maintaining and posting their own lists
- Tested for both desktop and mobile applications; created daily cronjob to automate daily updates

Adoptapedia: http://adoptapedia.com/

February 2013 - Present

- Created a website that serves as a widely used online resource for character designers and artists
- Developed cronjobs to update the group directory listing page daily

Oofoos: https://adoptapedia.com/oofoos/

March 2018 - Present

- Virtual Pet Site home to tiny creatures known as Oofoos
- Games on the site combine JavaScript and PHP capabilities to make for a seamless user experience

EDUCATION

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute B.S. Computer Science, Minor in Studio Arts Aug 2013 - May 2017